(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T05:06:51.637771",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
月夜のセレナーデ
Moonlit serenade...
白い薔薇は誰を想う
Whom does the white rose yearn for?
その身を震わせて
Trembling in its very body,
愛を歌うの
it sings of love.
零れ落ちた花びらが 寂しさの隠した
The scattered petals hid the traces of loneliness...
ねえ 早く迎えに来て
Hey, come welcome me quickly
最後のひとひらが落ちるその前に
before the very last petal falls.
今はどんな花とも群れないの
Now I won't flock with any flower;
あなただけを待ってる
I'm waiting only for you.
あなたとなら この体が 壊されたって構わない
Even if this body were broken being with you,
棘に触れたら傷付くわ その覚悟がないなら
if you're not prepared to be wounded by touching thorns,
いっそここから消えてよ
vanish from here right now!
重く閉ざした そう secret garden
A heavily closed, yes, secret garden.
夜風はリゾルート
The night wind is resolute,
白い薔薇は覚醒する
and the white roses awaken,
背中を押されるように
as if pushed from behind.
扉開いた
Opening the door,
ただ独りで枯れてゆくの?
are you going to wither away all alone?
待ってるだけじゃいられない
You can't just stand and wait.
衝動の赴くまま 茨の道を裸足で駆け抜けてく
Yielding to impulse, I run barefoot down the thorny path.
凛と咲き誇る華でありたい あなただけを求めて逢いに行くの
I want to be a flower blooming proudly, seeking only you.
どんな遠く離れていても見つけ出せる
No matter how far apart we are, I can find you.
暗い世界も怖くない
Even a dark world isn't scary
あなたを感じるから
because I feel you.
全て失ったっていい 二度と戻らない そう secret garden
Even if I lose everything, never to return—yes, secret garden.
今はどんな花とも群れないの
Now I won't flock with any flower;
あなただけを待ってる
I'm waiting only for you.
霞の向こう 私を呼ぶ
Passing through the haze, calling out to me,
鮮やかに燃える強き薔薇
a brightly burning, strong rose.
凛と咲き誇る華でありたい
I want to be a flower blooming proudly,
やっとここで出逢えた
at last able to meet you here.
あなたとなら この体が 壊されたって構わない
Even if this body were broken being with you,
棘に触れたら傷付くわ その覚悟があるのね
if you're prepared to be wounded by touching thorns—
手を取り合えば
if we take each other's hands,
広がる 誰も知らない そう sacred universe
it spreads wide: a sacred universe known to none.
やったー！
Yay!
お疲れ様でしたー！
That was fun!
さてじゃあちょっとね「Secret Garden」歌った後なんですけども、まずは自己紹介、7周年目の自己紹介！
So, that was us singing "Secret Garden." First, let's do self-introductions—our seventh anniversary self-introductions!
やっていきますかね、じゃあアキロゼから！
Shall we get started? Let's start with Akirose!
はーい！えー7年目の自己紹介いけます！ホロライブ1期生の夜空メル…あ、アキロゼこと、アキ・ローゼンタールです！ハロハロハロ、アロハ～！
Hiiie! This is the 7th-generation Hololive 1st Gen's Aki Rosenthal—Akirose! Hallo hallo hallo, aloha~!
そして！はい白上フブキですー！おっけーす、いぇーい！
And next up is Fubuki!
いつもシンプル！
Always simple!
ここどこ行ったんだよ！置いてかないでよ！
Where did you go?! Don't leave me behind!
寂しいじゃん！
I'm getting lonely!
私の心の…
My heart...
やめてくれ！やめてくれ！
Stop it! Stop it!
なんかみんなもいる中さ、最近じっくり自己紹介するの恥ずかしくなって
With everyone here, lately self-introductions are embarrassing.
恥ずかしいよ！
It's embarrassing!
やりやりやりやり！じゃそんな恥を捨てたはーちゃま！
Do it! Well, Haachama threw away that embarrassment!
見せてあげてよ！はーちゃま！
Show it to us, Haachama!
ワールドワイドの最高アイドル！はーちゃまこと赤井はあとです！
The worldwide top idol! Haachama, a.k.a. Akai Haato!
ほろライブの清楚担当、みんなのアイドル夏色まつり、まつりです！
Hololive's pure rep, everyone's idol Natsuiro Matsuri!
清楚！七年目も清楚でいくぜ！
Pure! I'll keep being pure in my 7th year too!
ちょっと聞こえない
I can't hear you.
でも清楚清楚か
But pure, huh?
でも最近ね、最近だいぶ落ち着きを取り戻し…
Lately I've regained quite a bit of my composure...
はい、ということでね、1曲目シークレットガーデンだったんですが、去年のね、周年で発表したオリジナル曲ということで、あれから1年経ちました！
The first song was "Secret Garden" from last year's anniversary!
あの楽曲からもう1年。いや、早いね！
A whole year since that song. Man, time flies!
あっという間でもう秒秒秒で…ほんと秒すぎる。
In the blink of an eye... seriously, it goes by in seconds.
今回はね、オープニングとしてあの歌わさせていただきましたけど、今年はオリジナル曲どうなんですか、はーちゃまちゃん？
How are things with original songs this year, Haachama-chan?
え？どう、どうなんだろう？
Eh? How would it be?
え、作ってるのもっとあるのかな？
Eh, are there more being made?
さあ、そしてそして、何やらステージが、見てくださいよ！
Now then, what's this, the stage, look at this!
今回のステージはなんとバーチャル世界の秋葉をイメージして、VTuberならではのデジタル感とか、あとはちょっと推し活感みたいなね、雰囲気もあって…
This stage is imagined as Akiba in the virtual world, with a digital feel...
YAGOって…YAGOやめて！
"YAGO"... Stop with "YAGO"!
一号店、二号店あるし！もうもろじゃんそれ！
There's a 1st branch, 2nd branch! That's totally it!
でもみんなのね、結構いろんな思い出の、なんていうの、ものたちがね、いろんなところにちりばめられてるんだよ。
Everyone's various memories and stuff are scattered all over.
で、とってもかっこよくてかわいいようなイメージとなっておりますので、そちらもぜひ注目してください。
It's designed to look super cool and cute, so please pay attention.
そしてさらに今回のハッシュタグは、こちら！
And furthermore, this time's hashtag is right here!
「電脳ぴゅあ大宣言」！ 1期生がそういっぱいエクステポストをしてくれるよね。
"#DennoPureDaiSengen"! 1st gen members will post lots of extras on X.
ちなみにこのハッシュタグですが、なんでこの名前かは最後まで見てくれたら、その秘密がわかるかもしれな…
If you watch until the end, you might find out the secret...
もし分からなかった場合はどうしたらいいですか？ はーちゃまが責任を取ります。
What if we don't understand? Haachama will take responsibility.
何でもする。いや、何でも何でも！
I'll do anything. No, anything anything!
ということでですね、このかっこかわいいステージみんな揃って色々歌っていきたいんですけども、まずはですね、ソロパートからやっていこうと思います！
We want to sing together, but first let's start with solo parts!
ソロの順番もあらかじめ発表しちゃいますか？ 1曲目歌う人は？
Shall we announce the solo order? Who sings the first song?
はい！まつりちゃん！まつりちゃん！
Yes! Matsuri-chan! Matsuri-chan!
まつりちゃんのソロはどんな感じなんですか？ この雰囲気にあった曲を選んだんで楽しみにしててください。
I chose a song that fits this atmosphere, so look forward to it.
はーちゃまのは？ はーちゃまは、えっと、森々で行きますのでお楽しみに！
Haachama is going with a lively style, so look forward to it!
どんな感じの曲ですか？ いや、この空間にぴったりで、まあ、新世界みたいな、地球みたいな、ちょっとでかい感じでいかせていただきます。
It fits this space like a new world, grand and Earth-like.
そして最後は白神なんですけど、白神も本当に自分の好きな楽曲を歌わせていただく予定でして、何やら騒がしい予感がしますのでお楽しみにしてください。
Shirakami will sing songs she likes, so please look forward to it.
ということでですね、ほい、トップバッターとして、まあちゃん、いかせていただきますよ！ それでは行きましょう、どうぞ！
So Matsuri-chan will go as the first batter! Here we go!
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? If you're dealing with a lotta woes
Unlucky? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Then you got to listen very close
Be happy! 靡まず目指せよ 生きてるんだし
Be happy! Keep on trying, never give up
目を逸した過去も 退屈な未来も
The past you have been running from, that boring future
カウンセリング
Still counseling you
やれやれ
Oh my, oh my
古今東西 ピースピース
Universal, peace, peace yeah
Unhappy?
Unlucky?
Be happy!
Undead
Undead, oh
ねぇ何だかどうして 戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Hey, why does it feel like I'm fighting all the time?
触れられない 触れたくもない
Can't touch it, don't even wanna try
過去の自分自分自分自分と
Past version of me, of me, of me, of me
もうとっくに死んでる
Is long dead and gone
透明な亡霊と対決
Transparent ghosts over my route
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
The childish and painful memories
ねぇ何だかどうして
Hey, why, why, why, why
なんかどうして
Somehow, why is it?
闘ってるようなそんな気がするの
I feel like I'm fighting...
触れられない過去の自分 自分 自分
Untouchable past self, self, self
と思う とっくに死んでる
Thinking I've been dead for a long time
透明な亡霊と対決
Confronting a transparent ghost
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
Deep within my childish, painful memories
残念？もう七年ね
Too bad? It's already seven years
あれ？どっちが良いアイロニーね 透かされてるのは現在の自分？
Huh? Which is better irony? Am I the one being seen through now?
ナンス？消えないレッテル YES！
Nonsense? An indelible label, YES!
弱音コンプレックス 取り憑かれているみたい
Weakness complex, like I'm being possessed
巻き付いたまま まだ離れない ありし日の自分
Wrapped around me, my past self still won't leave
あれと死んじゃいない お前と前の連鎖
Huh? Not dead. The chain between you and the past
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ 不幸に甘えて満足するなよ
To be alive is to keep changing. Don't indulge in misfortune and be satisfied!
幸せに習い倣ってさ なんだってよこの世はこの世は 期待外れファントムシティ
Learn from happiness and imitate it, what's this world, this world is a disappointing phantom city
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか 出会ってやっと始まる物語
Will an ogre or a snake appear next? A story that finally begins when we meet
人間化け物 ばっかりの物語 騒々しい大都市ピースピーススーパー未来
A story full of monsters, a noisy metropolis, peace peace super future
Can't change the past, Past & Future, run for the Future
カットイン 何だかどうして
Cut-in. Somehow, why...
未来になんぞ何の希望も期待も出来ないような気がして
Feeling like there's no hope or expectation for the future at all...
もう随分生きている 既視感とテンプレで食傷
I've lived for quite a long time, sick of déjà vu and clichés.
素敵な出来事の気配もない？ 積んだ経験の因果
Not even a hint of wonderful events? The karma of accumulated experience.
係累化けされたシワ 退屈な進化
Wrinkles turned into family ties, a boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ 飽きちゃった、慣れちゃったなんて
The point is I want stimulation. Saying I'm bored or used to it...
整っていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス 蓋されてく未来
Guidance falling into place, increasing compliance, a future being capped off.
吸い尽くして あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
Suck it all dry. This, that, and everything else all taste the same.
死んじゃいない お前と前の連鎖 いつの世も過去も未来も今にあるんだ
Not dead. The chain between you and the past. In any era, past and future exist right now.
生きていることを屈辱に果たすよ 目指せハッピーエンド
Turning being alive into humiliation, aim for a happy end!
死んじゃいない お前と言っているんだ 幸せは諦めてしまうなきっと
Not dead. I'm telling you, don't give up on happiness for sure.
人であれ ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ死んでいるのと同じ
Be human. Just getting used to suffering and enduring is the same as being dead.
屍のアンデッド 報われる未来
Corpse's undead, a future where things pay off.
幸せを目指せよ 生きているんだろう
Aim for happiness, you're alive, aren't you?
不幸に浸るも幸せになるのも そぜむ全部お前だから
Whether wallowing in misfortune or becoming happy, it's all you after all!
一切合切皆殺しだピースピーススーパー未来 Can't change the past, Past & Future, run for the Future
Slaughtering everything, peace peace super future, can't change the past, Past & Future, run for the Future.
人の在る所どこもれ出そう 生き抜こうぜ化け物ばかりの物語
Wherever people are, let's overflow. Let's survive a story full of monsters!
清く 正しく 美しく
Purely, righteously, beautifully...
8年目からは キレイな赤いハートに戻ることを 私は誓います
Starting from the 8th year, I swear to return to a clean, red heart.
誓います
I swear.
なんて言うと思った？
Did you think I'd say that?
行くぜの民な 雀頭でまで1人残さずにな 止まんねえような！叫べ！
Everyone here, without leaving a single person behind, won't stop! Shout!
Good god! I just wanna live honestly, 雑音ばかり, That's alright I'm gonna calm veryly
Good god! I just wanna live honestly, just noise, That's alright I'm gonna calm veryly
Every time I say what, 静観してよ優等生は, Fake up正義の味方
Every time I say what, stay quiet honor students, Fake up defenders of justice
You must be do call (Please, Please, Please), Do as I told, I'm sick of hearing just for yourself, for yourself words
正論的なのもういいって 物語に必要な そこまで言うなら演技切ってやるわ
I'm sick of principled arguments! If you say it's necessary for the story that much, I'll play my part to the end!
いい子のままでYes, No, No, No, Who is the Villain? だって I'm a Hero, I'm right, right, right
Staying a good girl, Yes, No, No, No, Who is the Villain? 'Cause I'm a Hero, I'm right, right, right
もうどっちだってそういい子のままでいっちゃんじゃん はいちゃんちゃん Yeah, Who is the Villain?
Whatever, staying a good girl like that, alright, that's that, Yeah, Who is the Villain?
One, two, three, go!
I give you my big RED HEART, My, my big RED HEART...
I'll be true to my big RED HEART, My, my big RED HEART...
いただきまーす♡
Let's dig in!♡
めちゃゴミ完♡全♡食!!
Super garbage, completely edible!!
お肉と野菜をトントンカトン☆
Chop the meat and veggies, chop chop☆
サクリンパ！揚げ物だって出来ちゃいます！
Crisp-crunch! You can even make fried food!
グットグットチョップチョップ・ルビンチュラビン・アビナンジ
Good good, chop chop, rubin chura bin, abinanji
はぁちゃまクッキング～ は～じまっちゃま～！
Haachama Cooking~ Let's start-chama~!
1. 調べない
1. Don't look it up
調べたやつからサクリンパ！
Crisp-crunch the ones you looked up!
ネットやレシピを見るのは 続々・ダメ・ダメ！
Looking at the net or recipes is banned, banned!
2. 測らない
2. Don't measure
測るのはゴミ！
Measuring is garbage!
自分量でも作れるのが 一流だぁおおい！
Being able to make it by eye is top-notch, hey!
3. はちゃめちゃアレンジ！
3. Messy arrangement!
最後はオリジナルの隠し味！
The end is the original secret ingredient!
これは料理の成長物語…！
This is a cooking growth story...
はぁちゃまカレーは5つ星☆☆☆☆☆
Haachama's curry is 5 stars ☆☆☆☆☆
スパイスマシマシで！
With extra spices!
作り方を今教えます。めんどいので省きます！
I'll teach you the recipe. It's a hassle, so I'll skip it!
(てめぇで勝手に想像しろ！)
(Use your own damn imagination!)
見た目はゴミでもめちゃ美味い 目指すは世界一！
Even if it looks like garbage, it's super delicious. Aiming to be the world's best!
あなたの胃袋掴んじゃう ぎゅっ。ぎゅっ。ぎゅっ。
I'll grab your stomach, squeeze, squeeze, squeeze.
はい… あーん♡
Here... Say 'aah'♡
友達減る見せたら減る
Friends decrease, showing it decreases them
左から2番目に中毒
Addicted to the second from the left
正気で美味い 完全食 お腹壊した人だぁれ？
Soberly delicious, complete meal. Who wrecked their stomach?
BAN! バイバイ！ おつるーじゃ！
BAN! Bye bye! Good job-chama!
It’s only love It’s only love
It's only love, It's only love
もしも願い一つだけ 叶うなら
If I could be granted just one wish
君の側で眠らせて どんな場所でもいいよ
Please let me sleep next to you, anyplace is fine
Beautiful world 迷わず君だけを見つめている
Beautiful world, without regrets my eyes are only on you
Beautiful boy 自分の美しさ まだ知らないの
Beautiful boy, you don't know yet just how beautiful you are
It’s only love
It's only love
眠れても覚めても
Whether sleeping or awake
少年マンガ
Shonen manga
夢見てばかり
Just dreaming away
自分が好きじゃないの
You don't like yourself?
何が欲しいか
What do you want?
分からなくて
Not knowing,
ただ欲しがって
Just wanting more
ぬるい涙が頬を伝う
Lukewarm tears run down your cheeks
言いたいことなんてない
I have nothing I want to say
ただもう一度会いたい
I just want to meet you once more
言いたいこと言えない 根性無しかもしれない それでいいけど
I can't say what I want, maybe I'm a coward, but that's alright
寝ても覚めても
Whether sleeping or awake
少年マンガ
Shonen manga
夢見てばかり
Just dreaming away
自分が好きじゃないの
You don't like yourself?
何が欲しいか
What do you want?
分からないの
Not knowing,
何が欲しいか分からなくて
Not knowing what you want
ただ欲しがって
Just wanting more
ぬるい涙が頬を伝う
Lukewarm tears run down your cheeks
言いたいことなんてない
I have nothing I want to say
ただもう一度会いたい
I just want to meet you once more
言いたいこと言えない 根性無しかもしれない それでいいけど
I can't say what I want, maybe I'm a coward, but that's alright
It’s only love
It's only love
もしも願い一つだけ 叶うなら
If I could be granted just one wish
君の側で眠らせて どんな場所でもいいよ
Please let me sleep next to you, anyplace is fine
Beautiful world 迷わず君だけを見つめている
Beautiful world, without regrets my eyes are only on you
Beautiful boy 自分の美しさ まだ知らないの
Beautiful boy, you don't know yet just how beautiful you are
It’s only love
It's only love
どんなことでも やってみて
No matter what it is, give everything a try
損をしたって 少し経験値上がる
Even if you get hurt, it's a valuable experience
新聞なんかいらない 肝心なことが載っていない
I don't need newspapers, the important things are not printed there
最近調子どうだい？ 元気にしているなら別にいいけど
How are you doing recently? If you are fine then that's good
僕の世界消えるまで 会えぬなら
If I can't meet you before my world ends
君の側で眠らせて どんな場所でも結構
Please let me sleep next to you, anyplace will do
Beautiful world 儚く過ぎて行く日々の中で
Beautiful world, as these fleeting days pass by
Beautiful boy 気分のムラは仕方ないね
Beautiful boy, it's natural to feel whimsical
もしも願い一つだけ 叶うなら
If I could be granted just one wish
君の側で眠らせて どんな場所でもいいよ
Please let me sleep next to you, anyplace is fine
Beautiful world 迷わず君だけを見つめている
Beautiful world, without regrets my eyes are only on you
Beautiful boy 自分の美しさ まだ知らないの
Beautiful boy, you don't know yet just how beautiful you are
It’s only love
It's only love
会えるなら
If I can't meet you...
君の側で眠らせて どんな場所でも結構
Please let me sleep next to you, anyplace will do
Beautiful world 儚く過ぎて行く日々の中で
Beautiful world, as these fleeting days pass by
Beautiful boy 気分のムラは仕方ないね
Beautiful boy, it's natural to feel whimsical
もしも願い一つだけ 叶うなら
If I could be granted just one wish
君の側で眠らせて どんな場所でもいいよ
Please let me sleep next to you, anyplace is fine
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
If I could have just one wish...
君の側で眠らせて
I'd like to sleep next to you.
どんな場所でもいいよ
It doesn't matter where.
Beautiful world
迷わず君だけを見つめている
Looking only at you without hesitation,
Beautiful boy
自分の美しさまだ知らないの It's only love
you don't know your own beauty yet. It's only love.
急ぐから仕損じる それも待ったなしの条件下
Since you're in a hurry, you'll mess up, no waiting allowed.
呪文のように唱えてさ 明日を占う
Chant it like a spell and predict tomorrow.
三月 不思議な感覚にとらわれすぎて
March, caught in a strange feeling,
ノーアイデア 偶然飛び込んだ手紙は
no idea, the letter that accidentally arrived
御伽噺の忘れ物 辛い布団の上はもう飽きたし
is a fairy tale's lost item. I'm tired of bed.
Right 惑うことなく大脱走 古い古い思い出 教室に見立てて
Right, a great escape! Using old memories as a textbook.
急ぐから仕損じる それも待ったなしの条件下
Since you're in a hurry, you'll mess up, no waiting allowed.
言い訳して逃げ出しちゃうなら最初からやるなよ
If you're gonna make excuses and run, don't start.
急ぐから仕損じる お先真っ暗って言うけれどさ
Since you're in a hurry, you'll mess up, they say it's pitch black,
見えないから面白い そうだろ 明日はどこですか
but it's fun because you can't see it! Where is tomorrow?
急ぐから仕損じる それも待ったなしの条件下
Since you're in a hurry, you'll mess up, no waiting allowed.
呪文のように唱えてさ 明日を占う
Chant it like a spell and predict tomorrow.
三月 不思議な感覚にとらわれすぎて
March, caught in a strange feeling,
ノーアイデア 偶然飛び込んだ手紙は
no idea, the letter that accidentally arrived
御伽噺の忘れ物 辛い布団の上はもう飽きたし
is a fairy tale's lost item. I'm tired of bed.
Right 惑うことなく大脱走 古い古い思い出 教室に見立てて
Right, a great escape! Using old memories as a textbook.
急ぐから仕損じる それも待ったなしの条件下
Since you're in a hurry, you'll mess up, no waiting allowed,
言い訳して逃げ出しちゃうなら最初からやるなよ
if you're gonna make excuses and run, don't start.
急ぐから仕損じる お先真っ暗って言うけれどさ
Since you're in a hurry, you'll mess up, they say it's pitch black,
見えないから面白い そうだろ 明日はどこですか
but it's fun because you can't see it! Where is tomorrow?
十月 あまりにも粗末で聴こえないような アイラブユー
October, an "I love you" too crude to be heard,
下り 沸いたよパノラマ 独りだけの運動会
a sudden panorama, a sports day for one alone,
暗い 生活にもサヨナラだし The light 見たリ得たりで大脱走
saying goodbye to dark life. The light, gaining through sight,
古い古い思い出 教室に見立てて 明日を占う
using old memories as a textbook to predict tomorrow.
急ぐから仕損じる 野暮な独りよがりは条件外
Since you're in a hurry, you'll mess up, selfish solo acts are out.
誰かが不幸になるようなビートなら鳴るなよ
Don't play beats that make someone unhappy.
急ぐから仕損じる つまらない時代って言うけれどさ
Since you're in a hurry, you'll mess up, they call it a boring era,
どうすれば面白くなるか考えるのはやるだけ無駄ではない
but thinking how to make it fun isn't a waste.
古い古い思い出 教室に見立てて 明日を占う
Using old memories as a textbook to predict tomorrow.
急ぐから仕損じる それも待ったなしの条件下
Since you're in a hurry, you'll mess up, no waiting allowed,
言い訳して逃げ出しちゃうなら最初からやるなよ
if you're gonna make excuses and run, don't start.
急ぐから仕損じる お先真っ暗って言うけれどさ
Since you're in a hurry, you'll mess up, they say it's pitch black,
見えないから面白い そうだろ 明日はどこですか
but it's fun because you can't see it! Where is tomorrow?
一のせで魔法も使えるよ 君は自由なんだから
With magic at the start, you're free, so
止めないで future symphony そう おのずと様相は不器用
don't stop the future symphony. Things are naturally a bit clumsy,
でも混ぜ合わせるよ この街に響いていけ
but let's mix them together and let it echo through this town!
ミュージック 奇なるミュージック 大丈夫 僕らが金鉱石
Music, strange music! It's okay, we are gold ore.
All quartets lead to...? Say la-la-la...
桜が 桜が
Cherry blossoms bloom and scatter,
咲いて散ったその後に 何が真実なのかは
what is the truth that comes after?
わかるから future melody
I know it, future melody.
そう 今は奏でて 愛の世界救うなんて 僕は信じてないけどね
Now playing, humming, saving the world? I don't really believe it, but...
今 目の前の君が 明日を生きていけるくらいには
Right now, the you before my eyes...
ありえない不条理は ぶっ飛ばしていけ
Blow away the impossible irrationality!
with 喜怒哀楽 余すな 全部惜しみもなく 言えないまま飲み込むなんてことはよして
With "Kisetsu Kairaku", without a single regret, not swallowing things unspoken,
with 喜怒哀楽 大丈夫さ どこまでも行くだろう
With "Kisetsu Kairaku", it'll be alright, I'll go anywhere with you.
All quartets lead to...? Say la-la-la...
おっしょ、ということでソロパートでした！
And so, that was solo part!
あれ？みんな、あれ、動き出して一緒に今
Wait, everyone is doing it together now?
何その動き！何その動き！こわっ！え、どうしたみんな！
What, what, what is that movement? What is that movement? Wait, scary!
なんかどこ行ってたの？ちゃんと見てくれてた？
Where were you going? Were you actually watching?
ずっと一緒に見てたよ。
I was watching together.
どこにいたんだよ！一番近くで見てた！
Where were you? We were watching from the very closest spot!
えっ、そうだったの？
Really? Is that so?
お腹は確かに今日多いなとか思ったけど。
There were so many stomachs today, I thought.
ということでですね、ソロパートだったんですけども、じゃあちょっと一人ずつね、改めて感想などなどなんですが、まつりちゃんの、アンド？
And so, those were the solo parts, but let's review them one by one. First is Matsuri-chan's—
はい！アンドットね！
Yes, Andetto!
やっぱこの雰囲気に合わせて選んだんですけど、なんかこの歌詞がすごいMVっぽく出してもらってね、良かった！めちゃめちゃ良かった！
I chose it to match this vibe, and the lyrics felt so MV-like, I was so happy!
そうなんですよ。かっこ可愛く歌えたかなと思います。
Right? I think we sang it cool and cute.
そしてはあちゃま！ほい！はあちゃまと一緒に踊りました！
And Haachama! We danced together!
ハートやばかったなんか。動き激しかった。後ろで撮ってたから。
Haato, the choreography was intense and cute!
そして新しく出たね「メガゴミ完全食」みんなどうだった？ゲーム要素たくさん入ってたもんでね、ね！
And the newly released "Mega Gomi Kanzen Shoku", how did everyone like it? It's full of gaming references!
そしてアキロゼは！どうだった？
And Akirose! How was it?
いや、結構ねがんばらせてもらったんだけど、すごく可愛いのよ。うふふ。してさ、
Well, I worked pretty hard, but it was so cute and I loved it!
この空間でね、こういう演出をね、ずっとずっとやりたいと思ってたから、ちょうどね、世界観にも合ってるし、すっごく頑張りました！
I've always wanted to do this kind of staging in this space, and since it matches the worldview, I worked really hard!
すっごく良かったよー！はーい、ありがとう！
So wonderful! Thank you!
最後はね、ちょっとあの、お腹フブライは引け目だったんですけど、なんかスコン部がやたら多かったんですけどね、ま、一緒にですね、やっぱ白上バンド曲がすごく好きなのでね、こちらのあの「桜のあと」歌わせていただきました！
And finally, Fubuki. There were so many Sukon-bu! I love Shirakami Band songs so much, so I chose to sing "Sakura no Ato".
ほんとにありがとうございます。めちゃめちゃ楽しかった！ずーんとね、トントン。
Thank you so much, it was so much fun!
そしてここからはですね、それぞれの期生の写真のイメージに合う楽曲を1曲チョイスして、全員で歌うプロデュース楽曲パートです！
And from here, we will each choose a song that matches our image and sing a producer song part together!
みんなどんな曲選んだのかめちゃめちゃ楽しみですね！はい。
I'm so excited to see what songs everyone chose!
まつりはね、まあ王道かなっていう曲を選んだんですけど、どうなの、どんな曲？
Matsuri chose an orthodox song, right? What kind of song?
ちゃまは、え、可愛い！可愛くて仲良しな曲にしました。なるほどね。
Chama chose a cute, lovey-dovey song!
アキロゼはね、まあ今ドキ感もありつつ、ま、ちょっとこうダークなみたいな。一番あるんじゃないかなみたいなね。
Akirose chose a song that feels a bit dark while being current, maybe the number one?
白上はですね、1期生だからこそ染みる曲。そうですね。染みる曲でございます。はい。
Fubuki chose a song that makes you feel emotional because it's first gen! Yes, a song that touches the heart.
ということでですね、皆さんもねコメントなどで予想して何が来るかなー！楽しみに！楽しみ！それではいきましょう皆さん、それではグループパート、せーの、スタートー！
And with that, everyone please guess in the comments what will come next! Look forward to it! Let's go everyone, "Group Part" ready, start!
好き嫌い好みの問題 どちらかといえば好きでした
No matter which you prefer, if I had to say, I love you.
乗りかかった船 止めちゃうほど 落ちぶれていないよ わかるでしょ
Tripped and fell, stopping halfway, you understand, right?
災害さあも結構れっつごー 次の扉よ 続け人生楽しんじゃって
Disaster is quite welcome, let's keep having fun with this crooked life!
行き先なんてどうでもいいの 次の好きの先 聞こえてるでしょ
Where we're heading doesn't matter, you can hear it, right?
アクセルしか踏まないよ
I only step on the accelerator,
止まり方なんて必要ないの　リサージャ
I don't need to know how to stop, Resizer.
涙もエンターテイン慣れ　カメラ止めんなよ
Getting used to entertaining even tears, don't stop the camera!
不甲斐ない私でもずっと歩いてきた道がある
Even a pathetic me has a path I've kept walking down,
つまりどうでもいいことなど何もなくってんだよ
meaning there was never anything pointless about it.
私感情上々いつだってここが最前線さ
My emotions are soaring, this is always the front line!
最後まで目を離さないで
Don't take your eyes off me until the very end!
そりゃ私だって悩みのひとつやふたつありますよ
Of course, even I have one or two worries.
眠れない夜の旅　束ねる
Bundling up sleepless nights of travel...
選択肢の続き
the continuation of choices.
バックアップなんてしたくないよ　オートセーブ切って挑むからリアなんだ
I don't want any backups; facing it with auto-save off makes it real!
緊張を脈動に変える　瞬きもすんなよ
Turning tension into pulsation, don't even blink!
変わんない私だからきっと繋いできた夢がある
Because I'm an unchanging me, there's a dream I've connected,
つまりどうでもいいことなど何もなくってんだよ
meaning there was never anything pointless about it.
私感情上々いつだって現場が最前線さ
My emotions are soaring, right here is always my current location!
今が最高潮さ　最後まで目を離さないで
This is the climax, don't take your eyes off me until the very end!
普通じゃなくて　特別じゃない　代わりのいない僕らだから
Because we're not ordinary, not special, and irreplaceable,
止まない雨を　明けない夜を　エライ傷を越えたんでしょ
we've overcome unending rain, sleepless nights, and heavy scars, right?
不甲斐ない私でもずっと歩いてきた道がある
Even a pathetic me has a path I've kept walking down,
つまりどうでもいいことなど何もなくってんだよ
meaning there was never anything pointless about it.
私感情上々いつだって現場が最前線さ
My emotions are soaring, the scene is always the front line!
最後まで目を離さないで
Don't take your eyes off me until the very end!
最後まで私負けないから
Because I won't lose until the very end!
出会った日のきらめき　重ね続けた偽りも
The sparkle of the day we met, and the falsehoods we kept piling up,
募る憧れも　カメラ止めるなよ
and our growing admiration—don't stop the camera!
回り回ったエネルギー　過客とノーテューズで
Swirling energy, with guests and no-use...
くすぶる物語　瞬きすんなよ
Smoldering story, don't blink!
スタートから！　だんだん！　したいときに！　したいでしょ！？　いっしょに！
From the start! Step by step! When you want to! You want to, right?! Together!
あたしたちはここにいます！　ここには夢がちゃんとかある
We are right here! Here, dreams truly exist.
フレンドなら友達でしょ？　「すきっ」って言ってみた
If we're friends, that makes us pals, right? I tried saying "I love you!"
「だいすきっ！」
"I love you!"
放課後なら当たり前のこと　さあさあ集まれ講堂に帰るな
After school, it's only natural—come on, gather in the auditorium, don't go home!
部活動だね活動しちゃうね　遊んでるんじゃありません！
It's club activities, we'll get active! We're not just playing around!
「ただいま。」ってあの子が言うよ　「おかえりー！」
"I'm home," that girl says. "Welcome back!"
みんなでいれば大丈夫
If we're all together, everything's fine!
エビバディセイ！　ともだちでいよーね！
Everybody say! Let's stay friends!
スタートから！　だんだん！　したいときに！　したいでしょ！？　いっしょに！　だいすきっ！
From the start! Step by step! When you want to! You want to, right?! Together! I love you!
あたしたちは楽しんでる！　24時間はいしゃいでる
We're having fun! Frolicking 24 hours a day!
屋上に真っ赤な太陽　かなり叫んでみた！　「げんきでーす！」
A bright red sun on the rooftop, I screamed out loud! "We're doing great!"
あたしたちはここにいます！　ここには夢がちゃんとかある
We are right here! Here, dreams truly exist.
フレンドなら友達でしょ？　「すきっ」って言ってみた　「だいすきっ！」
If we're friends, that makes us pals, right? I tried saying "I love you!" "I love you!"
キンコンカンコンからの下校タイム　「いやよわたしたちはまだ帰らない」
The chime rings for dismissal time. "No way, we're not going home yet!"
「やだよ～！」
"No way~!"
部活動だよ活躍しちゃうよ　新入部員募集中っ！
It's club activities, we're gonna shine! Accepting new members right now!
ごめんね。小さく言うよ　「内緒だよ？」
Sorry, I'll say it quietly. "Keep it a secret, okay?"
ケンカするほど仲がいいならネバギバアップ最強になれるね
If the more you fight, the closer you are, never give up, we can become the strongest!
スタートから！　だんだん！　したいときに！　したいでしょ！？　いっしょに！
From the start! Step by step! When you want to! You want to, right?! Together!
あたしたちは経験する！　食べて眠って賢くなる
We're gaining experience! Eating, sleeping, and getting wiser.
校庭に涼風吹いて　大きく手を振る　「また明日ねー！」
A cool breeze blows across the schoolyard, waving big! "See you tomorrow!"
あたしたちはここにいます！　ここには夢がちゃんとかある
We are right here! Here, dreams truly exist.
ふ・れ・ん・どならともだちでしょ
If we're friends, we're friends, right?
「すき」って言ってみた
I said "I like you"
だいすき！
Really like it!
みんながここにあつまれば
If everyone gathers here,
学校は特別になる
school becomes special.
今日が終わっても明日も
Even if today ends, tomorrow too,
笑顔で会えるね！
we'll meet with smiles!
私たちはここにいます！
We are here!
ここには夢がちゃんとある
Here is exactly where the dreams are.
ふ・れ・ん・どならともだちでしょ
If we're friends, we're friends, right?
だいすき ありがとう！
Really like it, thank you!
どうしてすぐ知ってしまうの
How'd you guess it right from the get go?
共振で苦しんで罵倒
Suffering as I wait for a combo
Q.更新で降る隕石抹消？
"Can I clear a line with a mino piece?"
悪くねえ
You're not bad, at least
興味ねえ救い遥かの常備ねえ薬食べBAD
I'm not interested in salvation, take bad meds
Q.超超えフル見た目暗号化？仮面ビオル
"Are there secret moves encrypted?"
常識ねえ狂いっぱで乱闘放置ゲーム
Common sense all gone; it's a fist fight
Q.送信で苦しいダメCancelは？草生える
"Why is it so hard to respond to mail?"
どうしてすぐ見てしまうの
How'd you see it right from the get go?
どうしてすぐ言ってしまうの
How'd you say it faster and then slow?
どうしてすぐ壊れちゃうかな
How'd you break it off just so easily?
(パパラパパラ)
(Pa-para-para-para)
近未来しか勝たん
Only time will tell who wins
ショッピングモールは出ないコート
The shopping mall's full of computer sims
小窓死とか加担モンティホールの経費でピンボール
Look through the display window or die
オイルマッサージ100分コース足湯付き 柚子を添えて
100-minute massage with foot bath
テテテテテトテトテトテトリス
Te-te-te-teto-teto-te-te-te-teto-ris
どうしてこんな目にににに
Why did this happen to me?
興味がないこと放置じゃないもの全部後回しで
Shove everything to the side, if it's not worth your time
知ってることは知らんぷり私は終わってる
I pretend not to know what I know
恥ずかしいか知ってるやつらの記憶けさせて
Throw all my memories away, forget my past mistakes
迷惑かけてごめんてば ねぇ誰か助けて
Sorry for all the trouble, I need help
妄信ですぐ引かれちゃうの狂信ですぐ引かれちゃうの知りたいくない
Gullible, I'm a hopeless romantic
知りたいくない知りたいくない
I don't wanna know
もう見ねえすぐ引かれSAD常識ねえ狂いてMAD行きたくない
I can't watch anymore, it makes me sad
臨時休業洗濯ボールナイチンゲールの配信ゲーム名刺交換の名シーン
Laundromat's closed from noon to 1
温泉旅行3泊4日食事付き 早く行きでえ
Head to the hot spring; 4 days long
テテテテテトテトテトテトリス
Te-te-te-teto-teto-te-te-te-teto-ris
共感性羞恥
My empathy's full of shame
うっとかそうとかいっそがしくって眠れないわ今日も
Manic or sad it's the same, I'm too tired
誰か早く殴って気絶させてくれよ
Someone please knock me out, I can't cope
人生キャンセルキャンセル界隈ぼんやりとした不安
Cancel out, can't sell out any of this
私のせい 私が悪いようだよ
It's my fault and I can't seem to fix this
興味が出ても本気でやっても全部空回りで
Even if I start to care, it's meaningless
知らないくせに嘘つき私は終わってる
All you do is just lie to my face
恥ずかしいか知ってるやつらの記憶けさせて
Throw all my memories away
迷惑かけてごめんてば ねぇ誰か助けて許して
Sorry for all the trouble, please forgive me!
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Never stop being an absolute idol!
輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shine forever
ずっとずっとずっと ステージにいて
Always, always, always stay on stage
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Never stop being an absolute idol!
私がいもし君のとこ離れたなら
If I were to leave your side,
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな いじわる考える
would you feel a little lonely? I'm mischievous
好きな人がいるのなら内緒にしてねぇ
If there's someone you like, keep it a secret
神様は将来と指輪をどこかに隠してね
God, hide the future and the ring somewhere
君の「好き」に合わせたんだ髪の色
I matched my hair color to your "likes"
私の中君だけで 過剰摂取は中毒へ
Inside me, it's only you / Overdose leads to addiction
責任とってね大好きです
Take responsibility, I love you!
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Never stop being an absolute idol!
優しい目も真面目な顔も
Even your gentle eyes and serious face
まぶしくて知ってる 私が言う
I know how dazzling it is, as I say it.
絶対そんなんで 輝いて
Always shining brightly like that.
星は街じゃ輝けないの
Stars cannot shine in the city streets.
眩しい君が 世界一だよ
You, shining so brightly, are number one in the world.
君の夢は何ですか？ 教えてほしい
What is your dream? I want you to tell me.
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても 覚悟はしてるから
Even if that dream isn't to be an idol, I'm prepared for it.
星のない空 それが当たり前で
A sky without stars, that was just normal.
暗い道に目が慣れずに 踏み出すのも怖かった
My eyes didn't adjust to the dark road, and taking a step was scary.
そんな時やっと見えた 光
At that moment, I finally saw the light.
絶対君は歌ってて
You are always singing,
ただのエゴと分かってても
even knowing it's just ego.
君はキラキラ衣装が似合う
You look great in sparkly outfits.
大きなステージで
On a big stage,
一列でも前で感じたい
I want to feel you even one row closer.
今日の歌い方なんか好きだな
I kind of like the way you sing today.
君の努力 私の愛 成り立つ黒歴史は
Your effort and my love, the dark history we build
努力って脆いの
is so fragile.
星の幸せを願った
I wished for the star's happiness,
だけど
but...
だって君はアイドルよ
Because you are an idol,
ずっと初めて目が合った日から
ever since the day our eyes first met.
今日も明日も君ばかりだ
Today, tomorrow, it's all about you.
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Never, ever quit being an idol.
これは報われない御伽話
This is an unrequited fairy tale,
恋よりももっと好きな魔法よ
a magic I love even more than love.
どうか解けないままで
Please, let it stay unbroken.
はーい！というこーとでー
Hi! So, um,
プロデューサーズ曲でしたー！
that was the Producer's song!
どうだったかな？お疲れ様！
How was it? Great job!
というわけでじゃあちょっと、えー、1曲目、1曲目はまずキラでございました！
So, let's talk about the first song, which was 'Kira'!
いやめっちゃいい曲だよね！めっちゃちょっとね、激しいダンスだったとともに好きなのもうー！
Man, what a great song! It had such intense choreography, but I love it so much!
いやもうなんか本当、この曲聴いて、絶対1期生これだってっていうね、ねえ、思いながらちょっと歌詞わけとかもね、そしていただいたんですけども、もうほんと
Seriously, listening to this song, I thought 'This is definitely the 1st gen song,' and while thinking that, we even got to split the lyrics, and really...
染みた！染みるっしょ！
It hit home! It really hits you!
そう！もう我々は常に最前線ということでね！
That's right! We are always on the front lines!
やったよ！いやもうね、1期生これからも頑張っていこう、最後まで目を離すんじゃないぞ！
We did it! And hey, 1st gen will keep doing our best from here on, don't take your eyes off us until the very end!
貯めるな貯めるなよ！そしてそして次は？
Don't hoard it! And next up is?
はい、アキロゼのね、アットリスをやらせていただきました！アットリス！いやこれはね、可愛かったから、いつかみんなでやってみたいなと思ったの！
Yes, I got to do AkiRosé's 'Atliss'! Atliss! Yeah, it was so cute, I thought I'd love for everyone to perform it someday!
で、グループのこういうフォーメーションとかを、ぐるぐるして、あーだなこーだなあったけども、そう、それをねちょっと頑張って貰っちゃった。
And figuring out the group formations and all that was tricky, but yeah, they worked hard on it for me.
ありがとみんな頑張ってくれて！いやめちゃめちゃ踊ったけど！
Thanks everyone for working hard! Even though we danced so much!
あーちゃんだってね、「いや無理だそんって」のが我々はだいぶムズっとしたけども！
Haato-chan even said, 'No way, that's impossible,' but for us it was pretty tricky too!
ま、そんな一面もね、愛してよっていうことで！はい、お願いしまーす。そして？
Well, please love that side of us too! Yes, please. And next?
はい、はーちゃまはフレンドたーい！フレンドしたかったー！フレンドじゃないけどで選びました。
Yes, Haachama's 'Friend Time'! I wanted to do 'Friend'! It's not 'Friend', but I chose it with that feeling.
あの後ろの映像でね、思い出アルバムね、気付いたみんな？良かった、モニター割れてなくてよかった！
With the video in the back, the memory album—did everyone notice? I'm so glad the monitor didn't break!
思い出、まだ割れてません！思い出はまだ割れてないです！
Memories aren't broken yet! The memories haven't broken yet!
はい、そしてまつり最後に絶対アイドル辞めないで！いやこれはね、まあまつりのエゴだったとしても、みんなにはアイドルでいて欲しいなという気持ちで選ばせていただきましたよー。
Yes, and finally Matsuri with 'Never, Ever Quit Being an Idol'! Well, even if it was my ego, I chose it with the feeling that I want you all to see us as idols forever.
この曲もなんか一筋でやるとやっぱ染みたね！たしかに！やっぱ7年目だからね！
Listening to this song straight through really hit home! True! Well, it's our 7th year after all!
すっごく よかったりする？
Isn't it super great?
おっ そして、このパートが 終わったということは？
Oh! And since this part is over, you know what that means?
じゃあ、そろそろ はしたぐの秘密を 教えてっちゃおうかな！
Well then, shall we finally reveal Hashtag's secret?
なんと、この はしたぐ なんだすが、新曲の タイトル になってます！
And guess what? This hashtag is actually the title of our new song!
えー！すごーい！やったー！
Eh?! Amazing! Yay!
ってことは、タイトルは 「電脳ぴょあおし大宣言」！？
That means the title is... "Cyber Pure Oshi Grand Declaration"?!
えー、どんな曲なんだろー！
Eh, I wonder what kind of song it is!
いや、ドキドキでございますけれども、「ぴょあおし大宣言」ってことは、なんかファンのみんなの曲？
Well, I'm super excited, but "Pure Oshi Grand Declaration" means it's a song for all the fans?
そういうことか！そしてくれるよな？応援してくれるよなっていう曲なのかー！
Is that it? A song asking us to support and cheer them on?!
そう！みんながね、この配信見てくれてるみんなが、私たちのこと 推しだよね？え？
Exactly! Everyone watching this stream right now... you guys stan us, right? Huh?
まさか他の人に浮気なんかしてないよね！？
You wouldn't be cheating on us with other girls, right?!
えー、四六時中私たちのことを考えてるよね！？え、一期生が推しだって宣言してくれるよねー！
Eh, you're thinking about us 24/7, right?! Eh, you're gonna declare that 1st Gen is your oshi, right?!
おー！しーたー！ってことで、それでは聞いてください！一期生の新曲、せーのっ！
Oh! Do it! With that said, please listen! 1st Generation's new song, ready, set—
「電脳ぴょあおし大宣言」！
"Cyber Pure Oshi Grand Declaration"!
はーい、これから配信始めるよ！みんな見てるー？
Hi everyone, we're starting the stream now! Are you watching?
今回はコラボ配信！
This time it's a collab stream!
あれれ？あれれ？コメントの熱量、なんだか少なくない？
Huh? Huh? The comment heat feels a little low, doesn't it?
まだまだ足りない！こんなののー！
That's not enough! Something like this—!
このこのこのこの このこのこのこの 電脳ぴょあ推し大宣言
This, this, this, this, this, this, this, this— Cyber Pure Oshi Grand Declaration!
推し変は許しません！！ わたしだけに尽くしてね
No oshi-switching allowed!! Devote yourself only to me, okay?
わたしだけに一筋 浮気じゃなきゃ嫌だ嫌だ ネッチャオゾ！
Only faithful to me—if you cheat, no way, no way! Let's get sticky!
他の子にちょちょちょっとでも よすみしてたらぶんぶんぶん滅！
Even if you sneak a peek at other girls just a tiny bit, bam bam bam destruction!
めらめらめんへらっ ほっぺふっくら にらめっこしましょう あっぷっぷーいっ！！
Blazing menhera, puffy cheeks, let's play a staring contest—appuppui!!
ほっぺたがおい可愛いでしょう 目移りはダメ！ほんとイヤイヤ
My cheeks are super cute, right? Wandering eyes are a no-go! Seriously no way!
いつも見て見て 私も待ってる あなたが推してくれる愛ちゃんのぜーんぶが
Always watch, watch, I'm waiting too. Everything about the Ai-chan you support—
私を支える栄養素♡
is the nutrient that supports me♡
(LOVE YOUぴゅ…) ラビラビラビっち 四六時中夢中
(LOVE YOU pyu...) Love-love-love-ic crazy 24/7 obsessed!
ねぇとっとととっとととっとと愛してほしい
Hey, love me faster and faster and faster!
HAPPY×3ぎゅっさー以上きゅはきゅよ やっぱりやっぱりやっぱりやっぱりはっきり
HAPPY x3 squeeze-more than enough, heart-heart! Really, really, really, really clearly!
(推して推して) はっきりはっきりはっきりはっきり ぴこぴこ キモチの パラメーターも超あがる
(Support and support) Clearly, clearly, clearly, clearly, the feeling's parameter goes way up too!
(単推し 神推し ■おしい)
(Oshi of one, god-oshi, ■-oshi)
もうほんとにほんとにほんとにほんとに わかってね！！
Really, really, really, really get it!!
おーい、みんな！ここまでついてこれれてる？この後もこの調子で行くよ！！
Hey everyone! Have you been keeping up so far? We'll keep going at this pace!
うりゃおい うりゃおい うりゃおい うりゃおい…
Uryaoi, uryaoi, uryaoi, uryaoi...
ちょっと待って なんて他の子褒めるの？
Wait a minute, why are you praising other girls?
(よすみ 迷惑発令中) 私以外も気になってるでしょ！
(Staring / glance nuisance alert) You're interested in others besides me, aren't you!
(ありえないよ ありえない)
(No way, no way)
他の子にちょちょちょっとだけ よすみしたよね！？
You peeked at other girls just a tiny bit, didn't you?!
うそマジ無理です
No way, seriously impossible.
DEATH (ピュア推し心じゃ)
DEATH (With a pure oshi heart)
私を尊んじゃ 指切りしてよ
Cherish me, let's pinky swear!
ハリセンボン×1000
Hari-senbon x1000!
心変わりしたらほんとに 拗ねる 怒る 泣いちゃうからね…！
If you change your mind, I'll really sulk, get mad, and cry...!
推し変はしてないね
You haven't changed your oshi, right?
「わたし」だけに尽くしてる
Devoting yourself only to "me"!
だってほらコメントが愛に溢れている
Because look, the comments are overflowing with love!
瀕死の HP みるみる回復♡ チート級ペチの 栄養補給♡♡♡
Dying HP recovering instantly ♡ Cheat-tier pechi nutritional supplement ♡♡♡
(パワーチャージ) ごめごめごめっちょ ごめごめごめっちょ
(Power charge! Gome gome gomettyo gome gome gomettyo)
ラビラビラビっち 四六時中夢中
Love-love-love-ic crazy 24/7 obsessed!
ねぇいっぱいっぱいっぱいっぱい愛してほしい
Hey, love me lots and lots and lots!
HAPPY×3ぎゅっさー以上きゅはきゅよ うったりうったりうったりうったり にっこりにっこりにっこりにっこり
HAPPY x3 squeeze-more than enough, heart-heart! Utari utari utari utari, nikkori nikkori nikkori nikkori!
私のため 日々、日々、推しごと励んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for working hard every single day to support me!
(単推し 神推し ■おしい) ぜったいぜったいぜったいぜったい
(Oshi of one, god-oshi, ■-oshi) Definitely, definitely, definitely, definitely!
ぜったいぜったいぜったいぜったい ぜったいぜったいぜったいぜったい
Definitely, definitely, definitely, definitely, definitely, definitely, definitely, definitely!
お願いね！！！
Please!!
このこのこのこの このこのこのこの このこのこのこの このこのこのこのー！！
Kono kono kono kono...
銀河の果てまで愛して(ほしい)
Love me to the ends of the galaxy (please)!
わあー！ということで、新曲でしたー！かわいいー！めちゃくちゃかわいいしー！
Wow! So that was our new song! So cute! Super cute!
なんかもう推しって感じで、みんなにもね！
It's like "totally oshi", and to everyone too!
ぜひ歌ったり踊ったりね、いっぱい楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいなという一曲になってるんだけど、どうだった？
We'd be so happy if you enjoy singing and dancing along to it, how was it?
いやもうやっぱ楽しいね、この曲に！しかもなんか四天王のどしゅみな曲、シークレットだったんだけどさー！
Yeah, it's just so much fun! And besides, it's the 4 heavenly kings' doshi-na song, it was a secret, but—
この曲聞いたときに、わ、これちょっと祭りちゃんにね、
When I heard this song, I thought, "Ah, Matsuri-chan—"
ちょっとがんばってもらうかなってとこでセリフのところとかさ、
maybe you can work hard on this part, like the spoken lines,"
そのね、祭りちゃんに、そう、歌い分けを
right, distributing the vocals
フブキがね、やってくれたんですよ。だからちょっとキメっぽいところは
to Matsuri-chan, Fubuki did that for us. So for the cool parts,
祭りちゃんかなと思って今回はね。
I thought they suited Matsuri-chan this time.
アキロゼもセクシーだったね。
Aki Rose was also sexy.
あ、よかった。
Ah, good.
触ったでしょ。ここ好きペンペンでね。
You touched it, didn't you? "I love this, slap slap" with—
お尻叩いた。
Slapped my butt.
あとさ、めっちゃ可愛い、祭りちゃんにじゅって言われたってとこ。
And also, Matsuri-chan saying "Juu" was so cute.
電脳ぴょーす大富豪
Cyber Pyo-s Billionaire
さて、ではここからは告知タイムです！
Now then, from here on is the announcement time!
今回のグッズはホロライブ1期生 Anniversary Parade！
This time's merchandise is Hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade!
こちら5月30日からカートオープンされていまーす！
It's been open in the cart starting May 30th!
皆さんチェックしてくれてると思いますが、内容見てみましょう！
I'm sure you've all checked it out, but let's take a look at the contents!
はい、まずキービジュアルはオットン先生に描いていただきました！
First, the key visual was drawn by Otton-sensei!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
今年のホロ全体での結成周年グッズのテーマはパレード！
This year's Hololive-wide anniversary merchandise theme is "Parade"!
その中でも我々1期生はマーチング隊です！
And among them, we 1st Gen are the marching band!
ではでは、1個ずつグッズを見ていきましょうかね、こちら！
Now then, let's look at the merchandise one by one, starting with this!
え、まずはこちら！プレミアムアクリル色紙！
First up is this! Premium Acrylic Shikishi!
こちら箔押し複製サイン入りです！よろしくお願いします！
This comes with a foil-stamped duplicate signature! Please check it out!
そして続いてはこちら！オフィシャルホロカスリーブ Anniversary Parade 1期生ver.です！
And next is this! Official Holoca Sleeve Anniversary Parade 1st Gen ver.!
翌日！ホロカがはいります！カードもスリーブも1期生です！お迎えしてください！
Holoca goes in! Both cards and sleeves are 1st Gen! Please pick them up!
そして次はこちら！
And next is this!
アクリルスタンド！可愛い！
Acrylic Stand! So cute!
今回のキービジュアルの衣装がアクリルスタンドになりましたよ。
The key visual outfits have become acrylic stands.
なんとプレミアムアクリル色紙に比べてそれぞれ表情が異なっちゃいますよ！
What's more, compared to the premium acrylic shikishi, their expressions are different!
可愛い！集めたくなっちゃうね。
So cute! Makes you want to collect them all.
そして最后はアキロゼ！
And finally, Aki Rose!
はい、なんと記念メダル出ちゃいます！
Yes, and commemorative medals are out!
こちらなんとケースと巾着がついて豪華な仕様になっておりまして、
This comes with a case and pouch for a luxurious specification,
記念ごとにデザインが異なっているのぜひぜひコレクションしたくなっちゃうアイテムなんじゃないのかなと思っております！
and the design changes for each anniversary, so I think it's an item you'll definitely want to collect!
タレントカラーとの思いも入っているのでぜひゲットしてね！
It incorporates the talent's colors and feelings, so please get yours!
そしてこちらのグッズなんですが、受注期間がですね、5月30日金曜日から今月6月30日、6月30日日曜日までなので
And as for this merchandise, the order period is from Friday, May 30th to Sunday, June 30th this month,
皆さん忘れずにごこうにゅうしてください！
so everyone please make sure to purchase it!
以上、周年グッズ告知でした！
That concludes the anniversary merchandise announcement!
え、そして、え、ちょっとまだあるよ！
Oh, and, um, there's still more!
えー、そして、次はメンバー個別の告知タイムです！
Um, and next is the individual member announcement time!
1つずつね、祭りちゃんから！
One by one, starting with Matsuri-chan!
はい！じゃあ、祭りは周年グッズの告知にしますよ！
Yes! Well then, Matsuri will announce her anniversary merchandise!
ということで、このあとですね、21時30分から祭りの個人の周年グッズが出ちゃいますので、ぜひぜひ買ってください！
So after this, at 21:30, Matsuri's personal anniversary merchandise will be released, so please, please buy it!
超可愛いイラストです！
It's super cute art!
めちゃゴミ完全食
Super Trash Complete Meal
本日の0時から各種配信サービスでもリリースされるのでお楽しみに！
It will also be released on various streaming services from midnight today, so look forward to it!
6周年グッズもあります！明日ですよ！
6th anniversary merchandise is also available! It's tomorrow!
6周年、6周年、あれ、7周年？6周年グッズも、あれ、7周年か！7周年グッズも、お楽しみに！
6th anniversary, 6th anniversary— wait, 7th anniversary? 6th anniversary goods— wait, 7th anniversary! 7th anniversary goods too, look forward to it!
はい、白上です！白上もですね、グッズが出るんですけども、こちらはですね、6月3日に発売予定でございまーす！
Yes, it's Fubuki! Fubuki's merchandise is also coming out, and it's scheduled to go on sale on June 3rd!
グッズの詳細などは よければ6月2日の配信をお楽しみに！
For details on the goods and more, look forward to the stream on June 2nd!
そして最後あきちゃん
And finally, Aki-chan!
はーい！はーい！はーい！はーい！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
え、あきろぜの、なんと2024かな？
Um, AkiRosenthal's, somehow in 2024, right?
自分の生誕祭のときに お披露目しました！
I unveiled it during my birthday celebration!
ミュージカルブレーメンの曲が ついに初披露になります！
The song for the Musical Bremen will finally be performed for the first time!
このあと24時リリース予定なので、
Since it's scheduled for release at midnight tonight,
ぜひいっぱい聞いたり歌ってみたり踊ってみたりして楽しんでもらえたらなと思ってます！
I hope you'll enjoy listening to it, singing, and dancing along!
あと、まあミュージックビデオとしてね、そのミュージカル部分だけ切り取ったものもあきろぜのチャンネルも是非見てください！
Also, we'll be releasing just the musical portion as a music video, so please check out AkiRosenthal's channel!
よろしくねー！
Please check it out!
はいじゃあ告知タイムでした！
Yes, so that was the notice time!
ということでですね、まあ7周年迎えて、え、そう8周年ですか？明日から？
So, celebrating our 7th anniversary... wait, the 8th anniversary? Starting tomorrow?
え？となると、あのちびっこにたとえると中学2年生？
Eh? If so, compared to a little kid, that's second year of middle school?
我々は中二病、中二病、中二病、中二病かな？
Are we eighth-grader syndrome, eighth-grader syndrome?
なんか、ふと、気が遠くなるような、なんかこれ以上解き放たれたらまずい
Suddenly it feels dizzying, like if we're unleashed any more, it's bad.
どうなっちゃうんだよ
What would happen?!
そう、まあね、これからものんびりやっていく一期生ではございますけどもね、これからも楽しくね活動していきますので皆さんよろしくお願いします！
Yes, well, we'll continue taking it easy as the 1st gen, so everyone, please look forward to working with us!
がんばろうぜ！がんばろうぜ！がんばろうぜ！
Let's do our best! Let's do our best!
はい、じゃあそれではですね、またそれぞれの配信でお会いしましょう！
Well then, let's meet again on our respective streams!
せーの、バイバーイ！
Ready, set, bye-bye!